<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[proteus4]]></title>
  <link href="http://proteus4.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://proteus4.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-15T05:41:05+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://proteus4.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[proteus4]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[proteus4@riseup.net]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Balls Deeps With Tor]]></title>
    <link href="http://proteus4.github.com/blog/2012/05/15/balls-deeps-with-tor/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-15T04:27:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://proteus4.github.com/blog/2012/05/15/balls-deeps-with-tor</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Five days ago, I wrote about first installing Tor and how it quickly changed my thoughts about anonymity and privacy on the Internet.</p>

<p>I mentioned that I had wiped one of my PCs and just reinstalled Linux on it when I noticed Tor in the available software. I installed it, began playing around with it, and felt a weird &#8220;freedom&#8221; knowing that I was, at the time, completely anonymous on the Internet.</p>

<p>Since that time, I&#8217;ve dived into Tor and the &#8220;darknet&#8221; head first. I took that PC and configured it so that any data traffic went over the Tor network. I also decided to completely separate my &#8220;anonymous&#8221; activites and my &#8220;non-anonymous&#8221; activities. It doesn&#8217;t make sense to mix the two on the same computer as that would greatly reduce my anonymity. For my regular online activites &#8212; e-mail, IRC, social networking, etc. &#8212; I continue to use my MacBook Pro. For everything else, however, I switched to using my &#8220;Tor PC&#8221;.</p>

<p>Then, a thought occured to me: <em>What if I want to be anonymous when I&#8217;m not at home?</em></p>

<p>To make a long story short, I went and bought a new laptop. A little drastic, perhaps, but I think it demonstrates just how I excited I am over this &#8220;new&#8221; (to me) technology.</p>

<p>I brought it home and immediately replaced the straight-from-the-factory Windows installation with a custom Linux installation. I installed a graphical desktop environment and all the tools I need &#8212; and then I set up Tor.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve been using the new laptop almost exclusively the last couple of days (other than checking my e-mail for work and &#8212; of course &#8212; Facebook) and it just seems so damn cool. Most of the time these last few days has been spent reading up on Tor, as well as anonymity, privacy, and security (and how to preserve all three).</p>

<p>A great deal of time has been invested ensuring that no &#8220;DNS Leakage&#8221; occurs, as that seems to be one of the biggest concerns when using Tor. Next up, I&#8217;ll be spending some time configuring the firewall on this laptop to only permit outbound traffic that is going over either Tor or my VPN service.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve already got an e-mail set up (completely anonymously), set up this blog (completely anonymously), and began participating on new IRC networks and channels (completely anonymously). It&#8217;s almost like I&#8217;m living a double life.</p>

<p>I like it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anonymity on the Internet]]></title>
    <link href="http://proteus4.github.com/blog/2012/05/10/anonymity-on-the-internet/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-10T08:24:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://proteus4.github.com/blog/2012/05/10/anonymity-on-the-internet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The last few days I have suddenly become obsessed with anonymity.</p>

<p>I had just wiped out my last installation of Microsoft Windows and replaced it with <a href="http://www.debian.org/">Debian GNU/Linux</a> and was installing various software packages when I noticed <a href="https://www.torproject.org/">Tor</a> in the list. I had first heard about tor many, many years ago but had never actually gotten around to trying it out. I decided to change that.</p>

<p>Let me start by saying that I don&#8217;t do anything on the internet that <em>requires</em> that I be anonymous. I don&#8217;t have any compelling reason to hide anything that I do. I&#8217;m actually very <em>public</em> on the Internet. My primary blog and Twitter account have RSS subscribers and followers that number in the four digits and they&#8217;re both under my real name.</p>

<p>Something I noticed, however, was that I felt some sort of innate &#8220;freedom&#8221; when I was surfing the web over Tor. I wasn&#8217;t signed into my any of my Google accounts so they weren&#8217;t tracking my searches. Every 15 minutes or so, I&#8217;d close my web browser and fire it back up again &#8212; wiping out my cache and cookies &#8212; so advertisers weren&#8217;t tracking me across web sites either.</p>

<p>It was a weird feeling and I liked it.</p>

<p>In the days since, I&#8217;ve became accustomed to this freedom. Although I still use Chrome on my MacBook Pro for most of my web browsing, I&#8217;ve began using this Linux box more and more for my &#8220;general surfing&#8221;. It&#8217;s somewhat comforting to know that, regardless of what web sites I visit, no one knows who I am.</p>

<p>Tor is now configured to start up automatically when my system boots, Firefox is configured to use it as a proxy, and 95% of my web browsing is now completely anonymous. Because Tor does slow things down quite a bit, I also have chrome installed. It&#8217;s only being used in a very few instances, however.</p>

<p>Over the next few posts, I&#8217;ll explain how this newfound privacy has changed my &#8220;Internet habits&#8221; and caused me to seek out even more ways to be anonymous on the Internet, from e-mail to IRC.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s a completely different experience and, unfortunately, it hasn&#8217;t been entirely without incident.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
